Gillian Stainsby fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Gillian Stainsby fonds
1988 - 1989
F-66
Q104890646
7 cm of textual records 21 sound recordings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Stainsby, Gillian
Gillian Stainsby received her Master's Degree at SFU for her thesis, "It's the Smell of Money": Women Shoreworkers of British Columbia. For further biographical information, see Appendix A3, "Acknowledgements," photocopied from Stainsby's thesis (available in hard-copy finding aid only).
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the provenance.
Fonds consists of transcripts and cassettes arising from Stainsby's master's thesis. Descriptive information for individual interviews has been transcribed from original cassette covers; see in the hard-copy finding aid Appendix 5 and item-level descriptions.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist into a single series.
Sound recordings; Textual records; Women; Labour
The fonds was donated by Gillian Stainsby.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. No further accruals are expected.
There are no access restrictions with respect to privacy: the transcripts are all open. Access to the sound recordings, however, is restricted due to the fragility of the storage medium; consult the reference archivist for more information on accessing the recordings. Copyright was not formally transferred to the Archives and therefore must be managed on a case-by-case basis; consult the reference archives for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available. Thesis acknowledgements and abstract, and interview summaries are available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Interviews, 1988 - 1989; F-66-1; 7 cm of textual records 21 sound recordings; Physical description: series includes 33 audio cassettes (originals and copies).
  published
  Series consists of transcripts and audio recordings arising from Gillian Stainsby's thesis. Note that all item-level Scope and content descriptions are transcriptions from the cassette cover of Stainsby's original recordings.
  For each interview there is a separate file for the transcripts and recording. The sound recording is treated as an item of the file. Typically there are two copies of each recording: the original audio cassette and a copy also on audio cassette later made by the Archives. In the case of one interview (file F-66-1-0-0-22, "A friend"), there is only the transcript, and no sound recording.
  - Addie transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    Textual records
    Open
    - Addie interview (Prince Rupert), 11 July 1988; F-66-1-0-0-1-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3138, Audio cassette OBJ-3139)
      Addie was a retiring net woman at Prince Rupert Fishermen's Coop. Interview recorded at work.
      Sound recordings
  - Frances transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Frances interview (New Westminster), 28 September 1988; F-66-1-0-0-2-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3140, Audio cassette OBJ-3141)
      Frances was a Tsmipshian woman who commuted annually between New Westminster and Prince Rupert. Interview recorded at her home in New Westminster.
  - Christina transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Christina interview (Prince Rupert), 15 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-3-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3142, Audio cassette OBJ-3143)
  - Joy transcript (2 copies), 1988; F-66-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Joy interview (Prince Rupert), 16 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-4-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3144, Audio cassette OBJ-3145, Audio cassette OBJ-3146)
      Joy was a young mother who had been active in (and employed by) the UFAWU. Interview recorded at her home.
  - Celeste transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Celeste interview (Prince Rupert), 17 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-5-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3147, Audio cassette OBJ-3148)
      Celeste was a young French-Canadian woman.
  - Anita transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Anita interview (Prince Rupert), 17 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-6-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3149, Audio cassette OBJ-3150)
      Anita was a young mother, daughter of Terry, born in Prince Rupert.
  - Virginia transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Virginia interview (Prince Rupert), 17 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-7-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3149, Audio cassette OBJ-3150)
      Virginia was a mother,m a Tahltan, night shift cannery charge hand.
  - Balwinder transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Balwinder interview (Prince Rupert), 18 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-8-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3151, Audio cassette OBJ-3152)
      Balwinder was an East Indian woman who immigrated to Prince Rupert around 1980. Interviewed at her home.
  - Rosa transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Rosa interview (Prince Rupert), 19 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-9-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3155, Audio cassette OBJ-3156)
      Rosa was a Portuguese immigrant, mother of four.
  - Dora transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Dora interview (Prince Rupert), 19 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-10-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3155, Audio cassette OBJ-3156)
      Dora was a Haida from Masset, mother of eight.
  - Penny transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Penny interview (Prince Rupert), 19 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-11-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3153, Audio cassette OBJ-3154)
      Penny was from Kitkatla.
  - Terry and Faye transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Terry and Faye interview (Prince Rupert), 20 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-12-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3157, Audio cassette OBJ-3158)
      Faye and Terry were floor lady and assistant floor lady at BC Packers Seal Cover plant before it was demolished, and at time of interview were at the BC Packers Prince Rupert plant, groundfish lines. Faye was a Scot; Terry was from Jersey. They were both immigrants.
  - Sandra transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Sandra interview (Prince Rupert), 21 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-13-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3151, Audio cassette OBJ-3152)
      Sandra was a young mother in a mixed native / white family. She was on the Board of Directors of one of the unions. Interviewed at her home in Prince Rupert.
  - Judy transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Judy interview (Prince Rupert), 21 October 1988; F-66-1-0-0-14-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3153, Audio cassette OBJ-3154)
      Judy did work often reserved for men.
  - Mary transcript, 1989; F-66-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Mary interview (Vancouver), 3 April 1989; F-66-1-0-0-15-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3159, Audio cassette OBJ-3160)
      Mary was a Japanese mother of three.
  - Judy transcript (2 copies), 1989; F-66-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Judy interview (Steveston), 12 April 1989; F-66-1-0-0-16-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3161, Audio cassette OBJ-3162)
      Judy was a mother of five who expected to be at BC Packers Imperial plant for another 25 years; very union-active.
  - Thelma transcript, 1989; F-66-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Thelma interview (Steveston), 12 April 1989; F-66-1-0-0-17-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3161, Audio cassette OBJ-3162)
      Thelma spent ten years at BC Packers Imperial plant in Steveston, but decided to quit due to a bad leg; very union-active.
  - Elsie transcript, 1989; F-66-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Elsie interview (Vancouver), 14 April 1989; F-66-1-0-0-18-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3163, Audio cassette OBJ-3164)
      Elsie was a Norwegian / Haida woman, chief shop stewart, who had worked in the fishery since 1975.
  - Barbara transcript, 1989; F-66-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Barbara interview (Burnaby), 15 April 1989; F-66-1-0-0-19-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3165, Audio cassette OBJ-3166)
  - Kuk transcript, 1989; F-66-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Kuk interview, 19 April 1989; F-66-1-0-0-20-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3167, Audio cassette OBJ-3168)
      Taped in the lunch room at Canadian Fish, herring season.
  - Mona transcript, 1989; F-66-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - small 66-1)
    - Mona interview (Prince Rupert), 23 June 1989; F-66-1-0-0-21-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-3169, Audio cassette OBJ-3170)
  - A friend transcript, 1988; F-66-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - small 66-1)